The Soul Living
Inside the Puppet
どりゃ～！
うお～！
（ミフネ）ひけ！　ひけ～！
Retreat… Retreat!
The Chakra Threads of world-class
Puppet Masters can control humans
（カンクロウ）
一流の傀儡使いのチャクラ糸は→
傀儡だけじゃなく
人も操ることができる。
as well as their puppets.
だが　チャクラ糸を切ってしまえば
操られてるヤツに害はないじゃん。
But once the Chakra Thread is cut,
there's no harm to the human.
かたじけない。
味方を殺めるところであった。
I'm indebted to you.
I was about to slay an ally.
傀儡使いには
傀儡使いの戦い方があるからな。
There's a special way to fight
between Puppet Users.
まっ
俺が引き受けるしかないじゃん。
And I'm the only one here
who can do this…
Right, Granny Chiyo?!
なあ　チヨバア！
（チヨバア）カンクロウ。
Kankuro…
ん？
《サソリ…。
Sasori…
わしのしてきたことは
間違いばかりじゃった。
I erred in everything I did…
But after meeting Naruto,
じゃが　ナルトに出会い
最後に正しいことができた。
I was able to do
the right thing in the end.
そして未来に希望を残し
死ねたはずじゃった。
I thought I died,
leaving some hope
for a bright future.
But…
じゃがな　やはりお前を前にすれば
後悔の過去を思い出してしまう。
As I stand before you,
I can't help
but regret the past… Sasori…
サソリよ…》
When are mother and father
coming back?
((サソリ：お父様と　お母様は
いつ戻られますか？
Well, they'll be gone a little bit longer…
うん　もう少し
先になるらしいのう。
(そうですか…))
I see…
《チヨバア：わしには　本当のことを
伝えることができなかった。
I couldn't bring myself
to tell him the truth…
両親の死を知らせるには
サソリは　あまりにも幼すぎた》
Sasori was too young to know
about his parents' deaths…
((うん？
Sasori…
(サソリ…))
《チヨバア：気づいておったのじゃ。
サソリは両親の死を…》
Sasori had already figured out,
that his parents were dead.
((コムシ：サソリ！　元気してるか？
Sasori! How've you been?
Huh?
この前の傀儡も
評判がよかったって→
Granny Chiyo said
your last puppet was a huge hit.
チヨバア様が言ってたぜ。
Some day, I want to be
a shinobi like you,
俺も　いつか　オメエの傀儡ぐらい
すげぇ！　って言われる忍に…。
where everyone praises my puppets…
（コムシ）おい！　聞いてんのかよ？
Hey! Are you listening?!
お～い　俺ですよ～。
Hey, it's me!
コムシが来ましたよ～。
Komushi has come
to see you!
おい！　返事しろって！
Hey! Answer me!
あ…。
わ…　わざとじゃないぞ。
悪かったよ。
H-Hey, I didn't mean it.
I'm sorry.
でも　俺の扱い
もしかして人形以下か？
But you're treating me worse
than a puppet.
まあ　お前のリアクションに→
Oh well, I might as well wait
until hell freezes over
いちいち落ち込んでたら
キリがないからな。
to get a response from you.
チヨバア様からの言づてだ。
I have a message from Granny Chiyo.
依頼しておいた
傀儡の納期を早め…。
She wants the puppets
she ordered sooner…
The Crow, Black Ant and Salamander…
（サソリ）烏　黒蟻　山椒魚。
Oh…
依頼書どおり　造形完了。
Everything she requested is done.
へ～っ　これが新作か。
しかし　ずいぶんと早く…。
Oh, so these are your new creations.
Man, that was quick…
待たせるのは嫌いだ。
I don't like to keep people waiting.
そうか…　そうだよな。
Yeah… That's true.
（コムシ）へ～っ…。
Hey… That's amazing.
大したもんだな。
まるで人の指みたいだ。
They look so human!
（サソリ）ふむ…。
あっ…　おっと　忘れるとこだった。
Oh, I almost forgot.
その新作の…
烏用の毒を　どうするか→
About your new creation…
She asked me to inquire about
the poison for the Crow puppet.
それも聞いとけって
言われたんだ。
Huh?
うん？
希少薬草ばっかじゃん　これ。
These are all rare medicinal plants!
これを調合するってのか？
You're gonna make
a mixture out of these?
This is going to require permission.
けど　こりゃ　許可証が必要だな。
よし！　このコムシ様が
掛け合ってやるからさ→
All right!
I, Komushi, will negotiate this!
So give me some time.
ちょっと待っててくれ…。
待つのは　イヤだ。
I don't want to wait.
だよな。　じゃ　行こうぜ。
I guess not. Then let's go!
It's me, Komushi!
（コムシ）コムシです。
なんじゃ？
What is it?
おお　伝言　伝えて…。
Oh… Did you relay my message…?
チヨバア様
サソリから　お願いがあるんだ。
Granny Chiyo, Sasori has a request.
なんじゃ？
What is it?
フム…　配合比率がわからんと
なんとも言えないが…。
There's not much I can say
without knowing the blending ratio
of the mixture.
おぬしのことじゃ。　問題なかろう。
But since this is coming from you,
I have no issues with it.
医薬部には　話をつけておく。
I'll clear it with
the Pharmaceuticals Division.
わしは研究の続きがあるゆえ
もう下がれ。
I'm in the middle of research,
so you may leave.
（コムシ）あ～あ　サソリは　いいよな。
Man, you've got it made, Sasori.
その歳で立派に
里の役に立ってるんだもんな。
You're still young, but you're already
contributing to the village.
チヨバア様も鼻が高いだろ。
Granny Chiyo must be
so proud of you.
Are you listening to me?
聞いてるのか？
Granny Chiyo is always
worried about you.
チヨバア様は　いつも
お前のこと気にかけてるんだぜ。
俺もさ　早くお前の傀儡みたいに→
I can't wait to be acknowledged
as a full-fledged shinobi…
一人前の忍として認められたいぜ。
just like your puppets!
うちの親は　いつも
俺を　ガキ扱いなんだよ。
My own parents still treat me
like a kid!
忍に向いてないって。
They tell me I'm not suited
to being a shinobi…
でも　今度
国境の警備を任されたんだ。
But this time,
I was assigned to border security.
そりゃ　ただの警備だけど
そこで手柄を立てれば…。
It's just guard duty,
but if I can prove myself…
コムシ！
こんな時間まで何してるの？
Komushi!
What have you been doing
at this hour?!
心配するでしょ。
I was so worried!
ちょっ…
やめてくれよ　かっこわるい。
Wait… Cut it out,
you're embarrassing me!
これから
俺だって警備の任務に…。
I'm going to be assigned border
security missions from now on…
任務なんて断ったっていいのよ！
You can turn down things
like missions!
母さんが
一生　面倒みてあげるから。
I'll take care of you
for the rest of my life.
（コムシ）だから　やめろって！
I want you to stop it!
サンキュー！　サソリ。
Thanks, Sasori!
聞いたぞ。　任務で
ケガをしたというではないか。
I heard that you were injured on duty?
ヘマをしちまって。　でもね…。
I messed up.
But…
なんと！　傀儡の腕を…。
That's…a puppet arm!
それだけじゃないんですよ！
That's not all!
ヘヘヘ！
前より強くなった気分です。
I feel stronger than before.
それに　本当　ピッタリなんだよな。
And it fits perfectly.
もともと
俺の体だったみたいなんすよ。
It feels like it's always been
a part of my body.
（コムシ）ぐわ～っ！
仕込みの毒を　自ら食らうとは…。
How could you ingest
your own poison?!
（コムシ）チヨバア様
アイツは…　アイツは悪くねえ。
Granny Chiyo…
He's… He's not to blame.
悪いのは　ドジを踏んだ俺…。
I'm the one…who messed up…
ぐわ～っ！
え～い！　サソリは！？
毒の配合比率は　まだか？
Where is Sasori?!
Do we have the blending ratio
of the poison yet?
うわ～っ！
治してください　治してください
治してください　治して！
Please heal him…
Heal him! Please!
右腕だって
あなたが　つけたんでしょ！？
You attached his right arm too, right?
Then his left arm can be…
なら　左腕も…。
足も　体も…
魂だって　治せるはずでしょ！
His legs, his body…
You can even heal his soul, can't you?!
(返して！　私のコムシを
治して　返してください！！))
Give him back to me!
Heal my Komushi and
give him back to me!
《痛ましい事故であった。
It was a painful accident.
コムシは　わしとサソリを
よく　つないでくれた。
Komushi was my link to Sasori…
それだけではない。
Not only that…
サソリにとっても　唯一といっていい
友じゃったのに…》
He was Sasori's only friend.
((サソリの近況は　どうじゃ？
How has Sasori been lately?
ふだんと変わりありませんよ。
The same as usual.
最近は
細かい傀儡のパーツを作ってますね。
He's been working on
small puppet parts recently.
(これが　本当に人の手みたいで…))
And they look like
real human hands…
((ん！？　なんじゃ？　まさか…。
偶然のはずじゃが…。
Huh? What?
Impossible. It has to be a coincidence…
何かが…。
But something is…
《思い過ごしで
あってくれればよいが…》
I hope my fears are ungrounded!
（サソリ）待たせるのは嫌いだ。
I don't like to make people wait.
目測では　もう少し
成長するかと思ったが…。
From what I can see,
I thought there'd be
a little more progress.
サソリ！　何をしておる！？
Sasori! What are you doing?!
ぎりぎり　規格のサイズに収まったか。
You barely got it to
the standard size…
サソリ…。
Sasori!
コムシじゃと！？
It's Komushi?!
(（サソリ）依頼どおり　造形完了))
As requested…
The model is finished.
《わしは　あやつが最もつらいとき
そばにいてやれなんだ。
I wasn't able to be at his side
when he was suffering the most.
愛情を最も欲したときにそばに…。
When he desperately needed love…
いや　本当は　あやつのもとから
口実をつくって逃げていた。
No, I made excuses and
distanced myself from him.
わしが　あやつを
あのように歪めてしまった。
I'm the one who distorted him.
すまぬ。　よみがえった死人が→
I'm sorry…
Much good it does at this point…
傀儡になったお前に
謝ったところで今更じゃが…》
An apology from a reanimated corpse
to the puppet that you are now!
Your technique is as sharp as ever.
技のキレは　さすがじゃん。
だが　闘志が宿ってねえ。
But you don't have any fighting spirit!
I guess Puppet Masters aren't good
at being a puppet, eh?
やっぱ　傀儡使いが操られてちゃ
ダメってことじゃん。
フン　若造が　わかったようなことを。
Inexperienced ones shouldn't act
as if they know….
この穢土転生という術を
あなどるでないぞ。
Don't make light of
the Reanimation Jutsu.
術者が本気になれば…。
If the user of the jutsu gets serious…
Oh, speak of the devil!
言うとるそばから…。
Reverse Secret White Technique…
裏白秘技　十機偽松の集！
Esematsu's Ten Puppets!
What?!
えっ　ワイヤーじゃと？
Wires?
Wha—?!
な…。
サソリも　このサソリの父と母も→
Sasori…as well as
Sasori's Mother and Father…
I recovered and repaired them.
俺が回収して直したんだ。
((サクラ：アイツは　サソリは言ってました。
Sasori told me…
自分は人形に
なりきれなかった人間だって。
that he was a human
who wasn't able to become a puppet.
An incomplete puppet with
a core that was living flesh…
生身の核を持つ
不完全な傀儡だって。
傀儡になった
お父さんと　お母さんに→
Do you think he wanted to
be closer to his parents
who had become puppets?
近づきたかったんですかね。
How could anyone want to
become a puppet without a soul?
魂のない人形に
なりたいだなんて。
そうかもな。　だけどよ→
Possibly…
But you know…
俺には　この傀儡
サソリの父と母に宿る魂を感じるぜ。
I can sense the souls of
Sasori's mother and father
inside these puppets.
サソリのヤツも
それを感じたと信じたい。
I'd like to believe that
Sasori felt it as well.
チヨバア様が言ってました。
Granny Chiyo said…
お父さんとお母さんの
最後の攻撃は→
that Sasori was able to see
his mother and father's final attack.
サソリに見えていた。　それでも
なぜかかわさなかったって。
But for some reason,
he didn't counter it.
(ああ　伝わったんだろうな。
父と母の魂の叫びってヤツがよ))
Yeah… It must've reached him.
The cry of his parents' souls.
確かに　俺は若造じゃん。
I admit I'm inexperienced.
だが
チャクラ糸を通して伝わってくる→
But I'm not so ignorant
that I couldn't feel
アンタの後悔や悲しみに
気づかないほど鈍感じゃないぜ。
your regret and sadness
through your Chakra Threads.
You say the first thing
that pops up in your mind!
ぬけぬけと思ったことを
言いおって。
That's why you're inexperienced!
だから　若造というんじゃ。
償いたくても償えないこともある。
There are things one wants
to atone for, but can't.
Besides, I'm a corpse.
ましてや　わしは死人じゃ。
どうすることもできんわい。
There's nothing I can do!
俺は　サソリに託されたんだ。
Sasori entrusted me…
I entrust you with the Father
and Mother puppets.
((サソリ：父と母の傀儡も
お前に託す))
Sasori entrusted you…?!
サソリが　おぬしに…。
Puppets that only Sasori could create.
（カンクロウ）さすが
サソリが作った傀儡だ。
仕込みはもちろん
指先に至るまで→
Their workings are so delicate…
all the way down to the fingertips.
繊細に作りこまれている。
《こやつもサソリ同様→
So he shares a love and
passion for puppets,
傀儡への並々ならぬ愛情を
持っておるのか》
just like Sasori did?
この２人には　サソリの魂が宿ってる。
Sasori's soul dwells in
these two puppets!
そして　その思いが→
And his love instilled the souls
of his parents in them too!
傀儡に父と母の魂をも宿らせた。
少なくともサソリは
そう感じていたはずだ。
Sasori, at least, was able to feel it.
Puppets with souls?!
傀儡に魂じゃと？
That's not all, Granny Chiyo…
それだけじゃないぜ　チヨバア。
父と母を操演したアンタの思いも→
The love you gave to
his Father and Mother puppets
魂となって
この２人に宿ってるんだ。
became a part of their souls.
Huh?
Sasori was aware of that.
サソリは　それをわかっていた。
すべてをひっくるめて
サソリは俺に…。
And he gave them all to me…
Rather, he entrusted them to me
いや　未来の忍世界に託したのさ。
for future generations
of the shinobi world.
それを受け継いで
伝えていくのも→
Passing it on is our duty too.
俺たちの役目ってわけじゃん。
サソリが…。
Sasori did that…?
たしかに　俺は　若造で→
Sure, I'm inexperienced and
in your eyes, a stranger.
アンタから見れば
他人かもしれねえ。
But my kid brother…
だが弟は　我愛羅は→
Gaara received your soul
and came back to life.
アンタの魂を貰って
生き返ったんだ。
とても他人とは　思えねえ。
So I'm not a stranger at all.
それに
チャクラ糸を通して感じるんだ。
And I can sense it through
the Chakra Threads.
サソリと父と母　家族の思いが→
Sasori and his mother and father…
The family's thoughts, their love…
Their souls are saying…
魂の声がこう言っている。
チヨバアを止めてやってくれってな。
"Please stop Granny Chiyo!"
家族…。
Family…
Mother!
((母さん！　たかが
家族の記念写真なんだから→
It's only a family portrait.
Don't be so stubborn.
そんなに強情にならなくても。
バカもん。
忍んでこその忍じゃ。
You fool! The meaning of
the word "shinobi" is to be stealthy!
そんなものを撮って
写真立てに飾り→
I will not take a photo,
to be put up as decoration
ホームパーチーなんぞで
「よいお写真ですね」なんて→
言われるのは
まっぴらごめんじゃ。
そ　そこまでは　言ってませんけど。
言ってるも同然じゃわい。
（サソリ）チヨバア様。
写真　一緒に撮るの嫌なの？
いや　そういうことを
言っておるのでは…。
もう　しようがないな。
おおう…　何をする！
む～。
(ああ！！))
それにしても　よき操演者に
引き継がれたものよ。
あっ！
チヨバア！！
な～んてな。　リアル死んだふり。
ゲヘ　ゲヘ　ゲヘヘヘヘヘ。
さて　サソリが父と母を→
置き土産として
置いていったのに→
わしが何も残さんわけには
いかんのう。
今のわしが
お前に残してやれるのは→
傀儡の奥義くらいのもんじゃ。
その身をもって学ぶがよい。
（カンクロウ）ちょっと待っ…。
（チヨバア）白秘技奥義　夢幻の集！
マジやべえじゃん！
（チヨバア）アッハッハ！
（カンクロウ）ガキの頃　あんなに
修業つけてくれって→
せがんだのに　里の未来なんか
どうでもいいって→
相手にしてくれなかったじゃん！
（チヨバア）わしも若かったからのう。
（カンクロウ）十分　ババアだったじゃん！
（チヨバア）アーハッハッハ！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート。
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』
２時間スペシャル。